<SCRIPT language="JavaScript">
 function setmlsrch (s) {
   if (typeof(top.query) != "undefined")
     top.query.document.forms[0].p_text.value=s;
 }
</SCRIPT>
<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href=/images/metalink/generic/kmstyles.css>
<p><B>In this Document</B><br><font size=-1>
&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#PURPOSE>Purpose</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#FAQ>Questions and Answers</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref1>How printer will be attached to Enterprise Linux system?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref2>What is CUPS?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref3>How to install CUPS?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref4>How to start CUPS?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref5>How to configure the CUPS server?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref6>How to Add/configure a printer?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref7>How do I add a Networked CUPS printer?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref8>How to find a list of printer drivers that work with Enterprise Linux?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref9>How to add unsupported printer drivers to Enterprise Linux system?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref10>How to set the default printer?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref11>How do I migrate print settings from one Red Hat Enterprise Linux3/RHEL4/Enterprise Linux 4 system to Enterprise Linux or another system using the GUI printer configuration tool?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref12>How to share printers from the CUPS printer server for Linux clients to use without using Samba in Enterprise Linux?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#aref13>Where can ask help?</A><br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;<A HREF=#REF>References</A><br>
</font><hr size=1><p>
@ (AuthWiz 2.5.2) <br>
@ <A HREF=# onClick='window.open("http://km.oraclecorp.com/awiz/awiz.pl?note="+document.lookup.WwwDocID.value)'>Click&nbsp;here</A>&nbsp;to&nbsp;edit&nbsp;in&nbsp;wizard. &nbsp;
<p>
<H2 class=km>Applies to: </H2> 
Linux Kernel - Version: 4.3<br>Linux x86-64<br>Linux x86<br>

<H2 class=km><A NAME="PURPOSE"></A>Purpose</H2>
Instructions for the reader: This FAQ document will cover to the most frequently reported how-to questions of Enterprise linux printer. The articles below do not include bugs/patches or troubleshooting.
<H2 class=km><A NAME="FAQ"></A>Questions and Answers</H2>
<h3>
How about Enterprise Linux support for printer?Which tool are usually used?</h3>Enterprise Linux has great support for printer,the right tool for the job is called CUPS (Common Unix Printing System). Enterprise Linux defaults to the CUPS printing system.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref1"></A>How printer will be attached to Enterprise Linux system?</H3>Four methods for attaching printer as following:<br><ul><li>&nbsp;Locally Attached Printer (LPT):Through a local parallel printer port</li><li>&nbsp;Locally Attached Printer (USB):Through a local port USB</li><li>&nbsp;Remotely Attached Printer (IPP):Using the Internet Printing Protocol (IPP)</li><li>&nbsp;Remotely Attached Printer (SMB-CIFS):Through the Microsoft Windows SMB-CIFS protocol (Microsoft Windows Sharing)</li></ul>&nbsp; Needn't extra configuration for support above functions for Enterprise Linux which had been set as default support when compiled kernel.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref2"></A>What is CUPS?</H3>CUPS is stand of Common Unix Printing System which is cross-platform printing system based upon the Internet Printing Protocol (&quot;IPP&quot;) which provides state-of-the-art printing capabilities for Linux, MacOS X, and UNIX.CUPS is open-source software developed and provided under the terms of the GNU General Public License with portions covered by the GNU Library General Public License.See more detail at: http://www.cups.org/<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref3"></A>How to install CUPS?</H3>In Enterprise Linux system, CUPS include as followed rpm packages:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp; cups-*<br>&nbsp;&nbsp; cups-libs-*<br>&nbsp;&nbsp; libgnomecups-*<br>&nbsp;&nbsp; hal-cups-utils-*<br>&nbsp; You can install above packages from the Enterprise Linux CD/DVD media or via up2date get those from Oracle Unbreakable Linux Network(ULN) repository.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref4"></A>How to start CUPS?</H3>Log in as root and run command:<br>&nbsp; <div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#/etc/init.d/cups start</code></div><br>Permanently effect start it when the system reboot as following command <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#chkconfig cups on</code></div><br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref5"></A>How to configure the CUPS server?</H3>The default CUPS server configuration in /etc/cups/cupsd.conf is sufficient for most users. For more detail introduction about &quot;Remote Printer Access&quot;,&quot;CUPS Remote Administration&quot;,&quot;Enable Support for Windows PCL Drivers&quot;,&quot;Setting Up a Remote Printer&quot; at section &quot;Configuration&quot; at http://www.gentoo.org/doc/en/printing-howto.xml.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref6"></A>How to Add/configure a printer?</H3>The simplest way is to walk through the Add Printer wizard in the CUPS web interface at http://localhost:631/admin.CUPS also includes a command line administration tool; ask help from the cups documentation if you prefer to use that available at http://www.cups.org/.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref7"></A>How do I add a Networked CUPS printer?</H3>IPP Printers are printers that are attached to a different Linux system on the same network running CUPS or at least with IPP support configured. The networked IPP printers are found via CUPS browsing as long as the print server and client can send and receive connections on UDP port 631.<br>Listed below are the steps to configure the CUPS IPP client to see all the allowed networked IPP printer:<br>1.Edit the /etc/hosts file to add the IP address and hostname of the CUPS server: <br><div class="kmnotebox">127.0.0.1       localhost.localdomain             localhost<br>172.168.10.1    printserver.mikel.org           printserver</div><br>2.Modify the /etc/cups/clients.conf file and specify the &quot;ServerName&quot;: <br><div class="kmnotebox">ServerName  printserver.mikel.org</div><br>3.Restart cups for the changes to take effect: <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">＃service cups restart</code></div><br>Use any of the tools listed below to verify if the networked IPP printers are detected:<br>tryprint.pl<br>redhat-config-printer<br>Once the printers are detected, its now possible to use them immediately without configuring the printer drivers and other settings locally.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref8"></A>How to find a list of printer drivers that work with Enterprise Linux?</H3>The drivers on the system can be found in the directory /usr/share/cups/model/,but may be hard to read or find exactly the model you are looking for. You can find the supported printer drivers in clearer way which is be listed &quot;New&quot; &gt; &quot;Select printer manufacturer and model&quot; dialog of the system-config-printer utility.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref9"></A>How to add unsupported printer drivers to Enterprise Linux system?</H3>Download the &quot;.exe&quot; file for the printer, and copy it into a temporary working directory. Then try extracting it with the unzip command as follows:<br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#unzip fooprint.exe</code></div><br>If the file unzips, there should be several directories with the Windows configuration files for the printer. Start looking in these directories for files ending with the &quot;.ppd&quot; extension.<br>If the vendor does not supply drivers for the printer, or the extracted driver file does not contain any usable PPD files,you might need to do some research at www.linuxprinting.org to see what drivers are compatible with your printer model. <br>There are two methods for adding unsupported print drivers to the system. <br>&nbsp;One is import the driver by gui printer configuration tool as followed:&nbsp;<br>1.Start the GUI printer configuration tool. Desktop: Applications -&gt; System Settings -&gt; Printing Command Line: system-config-printer <br>2.In the Menu, choose Action -&gt; Import PPD <br>3.In the next window, browse to where the PPD file is saved. <br>4.Select the PPD file, and click the &quot;Open&quot; button. <br>5.A pop-up box that confirms the import was succesful should show up.<br>Another is by walking through the Add Printer wizard in the CUPS web interface at http://localhost:631/admin,in the mean time you will experience the page of &quot;choose your printer maker&quot;,at the left bottom show you &quot;Or Provide a PPD File&quot; and click the button of &quot;Browse&quot; import the your driver.<br>&nbsp; <br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref10"></A>How to set the default printer?</H3>Log in as root and run command<br>&nbsp;<div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#system-config-printer</code></div><br>&nbsp; To set the default printer, select the printer from the printer list and click the Default button on the toolbar.<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref11"></A>How do I migrate print settings from one Red Hat Enterprise Linux3/RHEL4/Enterprise Linux 4 system to Enterprise Linux or another system using the GUI printer configuration tool?</H3>The method used to migrate the print settings from one system to another depends on the method used to administer the service. For GUI based printer configuration utility (system-config-printer), use the method outlined below.<br>1.From the command line, execute the following command on the old system:<br>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 3: <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#/usr/sbin/redhat-config-printer-tui --Xexport &gt; /tmp/settings.xml</code></div><br>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4: <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#/usr/sbin/redhat-config-printer-tui --Xexport &gt; /tmp/settings.xml</code></div><br>Enterprise Linux 4:<br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#/usr/sbin/system-config-printer-tui --Xexport &gt; /tmp/settings.xml</code></div><br>2.Copy the /tmp/settings.xml file from the old system to the new system: <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#scp /tmp/settings.xml user@newsystem.foodomain.com:/tmp</code></div><br>3.From the command line, execute the following command on the new system:<br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#/usr/sbin/system-config-printer-tui --Ximport &lt; /tmp/settings.xml</code></div><br>4.Restart the print services on the new system with the following command: <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#/sbin/service cups restart</code></div><br>Check the new system to see if the printers are showing up, enabled, and printing properly. Simply start up the GUI print configuration tool and look for the printers. Try sending some test print pages to the printers. <br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref12"></A>How to share printers from the CUPS printer server for Linux clients to use without using Samba in Enterprise Linux?</H3>Networked CUPS (IPP) printer server handles printers that are attached locally and have other Linux systems access it over a TCP/IP network without the need to configure Samba.<br>Using the Printer Configuration Tool all local printers can be exported to the network. Listed below are the steps on how to configure the Networked CUPS printer server:<br>1.Launch the Printer Configuration Tool using the command below: <br><div class="kmcodeblock" style="width:95%"><code class="km">#system-config-printer</code></div><br> 2.Click &quot;New&quot; to add a new printer. <br>3.Select &quot;Forward&quot; once the &quot;Add a new print queue&quot; window appears. <br>4.Enter a unique printer queue name and short description for the new printer at the &quot;Queue name&quot; window. <br>5.Click &quot;Forward&quot;, select &quot;Locally-connected&quot; from the &quot;Select a queue type&quot;. Usually /dev/lp0 is for a parallel printer while /dev/usb/lp0 is for a USB printer. If no devices appears, &quot;Rescan devices&quot; option can scan the computer for printers. <br>6.Click &quot;Forward&quot; and then &quot;Apply&quot; to complete the installation of the printer locally. <br>7.At the &quot;Printer Configuration&quot; window, select the newly created printer queue name and then select &quot;Sharing&quot; from the &quot;Action&quot; tab. <br>8.On the &quot;Queue&quot; tab, enable the option &quot;This queue is available to other computers&quot;. <br>9.Now from the &quot;Queue&quot; tab, click on &quot;Edit&quot; to configure the printer if its accessible from &quot;All hosts&quot; or via &quot;Network device&quot; or &quot;Network address&quot; or from a &quot;Single IP address&quot;. <br>10.Click &quot;OK&quot; and then restart cups service for the changes to take effect. <br>service cups restart<br><br>
<H3 class=km><A NAME="aref13"></A>Where can ask help?</H3>These are some links below that may help you in setting up, using and manging printers:<br><ol><li><a title="CUPS homepage" href="http://www.cpus.org/">CUPS homepage</a></li><li><a title="Linux Printing" href="http://linuxprinting.org">Linux Printing</a></li><li><a title="Oracle Linux forum" href="http://forums.oracle.com/forums/forum.jspa?forumID=135">Oracle Linux forum</a></li><li>To open an Service Request(SR) for a source of help at <a href="http://www.metalink.oracle.com/" title="Metalink">Metalink</a>.</li></ol><br><br><br><br>
<H2 class=km><A NAME="REF"></A>References</H2>
<A HREF='http://www.cpus.org/' TARGET=_blank>http://www.cpus.org/</A><br>
<A HREF='http://linuxprinting.org' TARGET=_blank>http://linuxprinting.org</A><br>
<A HREF='http://forums.oracle.com/forums/forum.jspa?forumID=135' TARGET=_blank>http://forums.oracle.com/forums/forum.jspa?forumID=135</A><br>



<HR>
<BR>
Help us improve our service.  Please <a href="showdoc?db=NOT&id=264463.1&blackframe=0" onClick="window.open(this.href,'popup','width=800,height=500,menubar=0');return false;">email</a> us your comments for this document.
